[{
"questionText": "All colleges will ask for a personal essay.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "true", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "false", "val": "b"}],
"correctAnswer": "b",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "basic"
},

{
"questionText": "What is the word limit for CommonApp essays?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "1000", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "500", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "550", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "650", "val": "d"}, {"txt": "700", "val": "e"}],
"correctAnswer": "d",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "commonapp"
},

{
"questionText": "For CommonApp, students will be asked to choose to respond to _____ out of _____ 5 prompts.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "1, 5", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "3,6", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "2,10", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "1,10", "val": "d"}, {"txt": "1,8", "val": "e"}],
"correctAnswer": "a",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "commonapp"
},

{
"questionText": "For CommonApp, students should aim to reach _____ of the word limit or use full range.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "50%", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "60%", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "70%", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "80%", "val": "d"}, {"txt": "99%", "val": "e"}],
"correctAnswer": "d",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "commonapp"
},

{
"questionText": "Students shouldn’t talk about failure in their personal essays.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "True. Admissions committees want to hear the good parts of a student’s life.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "False. Admission committee want to see growth", "val": "b"}],
"correctAnswer": "b",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "commonapp"
},

{
"questionText": "In most cases, which isn’t a writing section listed on an application?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "fictional essay", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "short response", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "supplemental essay", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "disciplinary history", "val": "d"}, {"txt": "optional information", "val": "e"}],
"correctAnswer": "a",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "basic"
},
{
"questionText": "The essay prompt asks the student to write about a setback. What is the admissions committee looking for?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "essay about family’s setback", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "essay about a peer’s setback and what they learned from the experience", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "essay about the student’s setback and what they learned from the experience", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "essay about student’s setback", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "c",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "answer"}
,
{"questionText": "A student writes a great essay but it’s 500 words over the word limit. What should the student do?",
"possibleAnswers":[{"txt": "Leave the essay as is. If the essay is that great, the admissions committee won’t care.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "Leave the essay as is. The student can always be the exception to the rule.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "Condense the original essay but still main their original points. The admissions committee will see the student follows directions.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "Write a new essay from scratch. The student can always be the exception to the rule.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "c",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "basic"}
,
{"questionText": "What’s a helpful tip to write a strong essay but stay within the word limit?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "Don’t go into detail.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "Write in active voice. Avoid writing in passive voice or voice of beings.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "Use I-Statements in every sentence.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "Ask a peer to write the essay.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "b",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "basic"}
,
{"questionText": "When writing about disciplinary history, what isn’t a good reason for students for students to ask their guidance counselor for help?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "The guidance counselor knows what the high school reports to colleges, so the student knows what to share", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "The guidance counselor is expected to support the student and talk about how good they are.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "The guidance counselor can write a letter of recommendation to discuss how the student’s grown from the experience", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "If the student takes responsibility and is proactive about the process, they can earn the guidance counselor’s trust.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "b",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "dhistory"}
,
{
"questionText": "What shouldn’t the student do when writing about disciplinary history?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "Overshare. Write about every detail.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "Be honest.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "Take responsibility.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "Use guidance counselor for help.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "a",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "dhistory"}
,
{"questionText": "If a student has a record of disciplinary history, the school will never consider the student.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "True. The school wants the perfect student.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "True. The damage has been done and the student can’t change.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "False. Some infractions will be deemed more seriously than others, especially if the student demonstrates growth.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "False. As long as the student has perfect grades, the school won’t reject a student over their disciplinary history", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "c",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "dhistory"}
,
{
"questionText": "What shouldn’t students write about in the optional essay?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "Gap in timeline/educational history", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "a failed course", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "family demands that impacted the student’s ability to perform well or be involved", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "additional achievements", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "c",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "optional"
},

{
"questionText": "Students should always submit their first draft.",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "True. The student doesn’t need someone to proofread because they have spellcheck.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "True. The first draft is the perfect draft. No need to overthink.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "False. Each draft needs to be proofread or read out loud.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "False. The student should submit the 63rd draft.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "c",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "basic"
},

{
"questionText": "For supplemental essays, students do not receive the topic ahead of time so it can be challenging to prepare for this essay in advance. What tip shouldn’t students follow?",
"possibleAnswers": [{"txt": "Procrastinate.", "val": "a"}, {"txt": "Create a 'bank' of influential people or events to speed up the process.", "val": "b"}, {"txt": "Write a list about unique resources or attributes about the school.", "val": "c"}, {"txt": "Write a list about personal characters that will help the student stand out from other applicants.", "val": "d"}],
"correctAnswer": "a",
"category": "essays",
"subcategory": "supplemental"
}]
